PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(spring pinging) (ball bouncing)
（弹簧乒乒） （小球乓乓）
(lightbulb pinging)
（灯泡叮~）
- We've seen that every display device
- 我们已经知道每种播放设备
can represent only a region of colors
只能还原出部分的
within the perceivable color space,
可感知色彩
and this region we call a gamut.
而这部分颜色被称为色域
But inside the computer, where colors
但在电脑中 颜色
are represented digitally, they're just numbers,
是数字化表示的 它们仅仅是一些数字
and they can represent the entire perceivable color space.
它们可以代表整个可感知色彩空间
But when we send the film to a theater,
但当我们把电影发给剧院的时候
we need to match the color space
我们需要将色彩空间匹配至
of the projector being used,
所使用的投影仪的色彩空间
and that's the job of the color grading process.
而这个工作就被称为颜色映射过程
It's to fill out the color space
它会用尽投影仪
available within that projector
所有可用的颜色
and sort of constrain any colors
并在一定程度上限制
that don't fit within that device gamut.
超出设备色域的颜色
And that's why I'm joined here by
这就是为什么我要在此邀请
Mark Dinicola, our colorist.
Mark Dinicola 我们的调色师
Hey Mark.
嘿 Mark
- Hello again, Dom.
- 你又好呀 Dom
- [Dom] So tell me about some of the different
- 【Dom】告诉我一些你为电影
types of grades that you do for a movie.
做过的不同类的颜色映射吧
- [Mark] Well, we do the film grade;
- 【Mark】嗯 我们做过胶片颜色映射
the digital cinema grade, that's
数字影院颜色映射
for digital projectors in theaters;
这是为影院的数字投影仪做的
as well as grades for home viewing in both
我们也为家用环境做色彩映射
high definition and standard definition.
包括了高清和标清
- So film versus digital grading?
- 所以胶片颜色映射对数字颜色映射
What's that like?
它们是什么样的？
- [Mark] Well, as you mentioned color gamut,
- 【Mark】嗯 既然你提到了色域
the film has a totally different color gamut
胶片的色域和
than, say, digital cinema.
数字影院的色域完全不一样
Especially film, the brighter saturated colors
特别是胶片 又明亮又高饱和的颜色
aren't as available, so say on Cars 2,
并不好获得 所以在《汽车总动员 2》中
where we had McQueen, a bright saturated red car,
闪电麦昆 是一辆明亮而艳丽的红色汽车
we had an issue with the film grade.
我们在色彩映射上就出了个问题
We had to decide, is it more important
我们必须决定 是让闪电麦昆
that he's bright and saturated,
更亮更艳丽重要呢
or is better to have proper contrast?
还是让他具有正确的对比度更重要？
- Wow, okay.
- 喔 好吧
Any other stories or challenges on films past?
在过去的电影中还有其他的故事或挑战么？
- Pretty much any film that has red.
- 大部分都是具有红色色彩的电影
Inside Out was an interesting one.
《头脑特工队》就是很有趣的一个
It was a very saturated film,
它是一部饱和度非常高的电影
with so many different colors,
有那么多不同的颜色
like Bing Bong is bright pink.
像冰棒就是亮粉色的
He tends to go brown on film,
他在胶片上就会发棕色
so we had to carefully craft the grade for film
然后我们就得小心的处理为电影做的颜色映射
for that movie to make sure he stayed pink.
以保证电影中他是粉色的
- So in the next exercise, you're gonna have a chance
- 所以在下一个练习中 你将有机会
to explore what some of the different gamuts look like
探索几种不同的色域下
with some scenes from our movies,
我们的电影的样子
and we're gonna ask you a few questions
我们也会问你几个问题
to make sure you understand the concepts.
以确保你明白了这些概念
Thanks for sticking with us.
谢谢你一路紧跟
Enjoy! aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
学地开心！ aimozhen.com/pixarinabox